Alejandro Morales Papers M1937
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives
Alejandro Morales Papers
circa 1953-2012
M1937
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives
17.0 Linear feet
Collection contains drafts, research, editorial material, correspondence, and reviews of Morales' major publications; and personal correspondence, ephemera, and miscellaneous material.
Morales, Alejandro, 1944-
Biographical Note
Alejandro Morales, the son of Mexican immigrants, was born in Montebello, California and grew up in Simons, the company town of the Simons Brick Yard #3, bordering Montebello. He earned his B.A. from California State University, Los Angeles, and a M.A. and Ph.D. from Rutgers University. Morales is currently a professor in the Department of Chicano/Latino Studies at the University of California, Irvine. Morales, as a novelist and professor, was awarded the Luis Leal Award for Distinction in Chicano/Latino Literature in 2007 from the University of California, Santa Barbara.
Morales literary works include: Caras Viejas y vino Nuevo (1975); La Verdad sin voz (1979); Reto in Parasio (1983); The Brick People (1988); The Rag Doll Plagues (1992); Barrio on the Edge (1997); Waiting to Happen (2001); Pequena Nacion (2005); and The Captain of All these Men of Death (2008).
Access to Collection
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Acquisition Information
Purchased, 2013; Accession Number 2013-015
Scope and Contents
Preliminary listing of contents, nominally organized by major publication (i.e. Pequeno Nacion, Reto el el Paraiso, Waiting to Happen, The Place of the White Heron, The Brick People, etc.)
Morales, Alejandro, 1944-; California--Fiction; Mexican American literature; Mexican Americans--California--Fiction
- Alejandro Morales: Pequena Nacion: Paperback. Editorial Orbis Press 2008 (Box  1, Folder  1)
- Alejandro Morales Short fiction from 1409 espanol street 1 compbook (Box  1, Folder  2)
- Alejandro Morales Short fiction from 1409 espanol street 2 compbook (Box  1, Folder  3)
- Alejandro Morales Short fiction from 1409 espanol street 3 compbook (Box  1, Folder  4)
- Alejandro Morales Short fiction from 1409 espanol street 4 compbook (Box  1, Folder  5)
- A. Morales: the Sign final draft (Box  1, Folder  6)
- A.Morales: the Sign I: Notebook (Box  1, Folder  7)
- A.Morales: the Sign Ii: Notebook (Box  1, Folder  8)
- A.Morales Calcary cemetery & mausoleum 1996. 100th anniversary. Programs, flyers, etc. (Box  1, Folder  9)
- A.Morales: Nacion Pequena notes, email correspondence (Box  1, Folder  10)
- A.Morales: Micaela Clemencia Felicitas y poca 1 compbook (Box  2, Folder  1)
- A.Morales: Micaela Clemencia Felicitas y poca 2 compbook (Box  2, Folder  2)
- A.Morales: Micaela Clemencia Felicitas y poca 3 compbook (Box  2, Folder  3)
- A.Morales: Micaela Clemencia Felicitas y poca 4 compbook (Box  2, Folder  4)
- Adam Spires correspondence. intro mapping acadia. Aztlan and utopia (Box  2, Folder  5)
- Pequena Nacion (edited) (Box  2, Folder  6)
- Little Nation: english manuscript. M.Herrera Sobek "blurb" (Box  2, Folder  7)
- La Penca/Garden of Versailles/ the Parable of Quetzali (Box  2, Folder  8)
- La Penca (spanish/edited) News clips, gabriel miro flyer, map, J.D Wolcott (Box  2, Folder  9)
- Pequena Nacion/versian nueva Orbit Press 2008 (Box  3, Folder  1)
- Jeffrey Reiman:The rich get richer and the poor get prison:paperback. Pearson allyn and bacon 2004. Tres Novelas cortas "connectciones introducidas" (Box  3, Folder  2)
- Ana Lorino/Adam Spires correspondence concepcion (draft) (Box  3, Folder  3)
- September 11: West Coast Writers Approach Ground Zero: Paperback. Edited by Jeff Meyers (Box  3, Folder  4)
- Under the fifth Sun: Paperback. Heyday book 2002. Edited by Rick Heide (Box  3, Folder  5)
- Tres Novelas Cortas version nueva 1 (Box  4, Folder  1)
- Tres Novelas Cortas version nueva 2 (Box  4, Folder  2)
- Quetzali and The Sign (Box  4, Folder  3)
- Little Nation with introduction (Box  4, Folder  4)
- Kristen Buckley/Adam Spires/ Nash Candelaria correspondence. Host Publications 20th anniversary (Box  4, Folder  5)
- Reto en el Paraiso (copy of original manuscript) part 1 (Box  4, Folder  6)
- Reto en el Paraiso (copy of original manuscript) part 2 (Box  4, Folder  7)
- First american title insurance company (photos) (Box  4, Folder  8)
- Biligual Press/Editorial Biligue. Books of the southwest (Box  4, Folder  9)
- Reto en el Paraiso annotated draft (Box  5, Folder  1)
- Reto en el Paraiso annotated draft (Box  5, Folder  2)
- Reto en el Paraiso (final) part 1. Pages 1-166 (Box  5, Folder  3)
- Reto en el Paraiso (final) part 2. Pages 167-310 (Box  5, Folder  4)
- Reto en el Paraiso (final) part 1. Pages 311-434 (Box  5, Folder  5)
- Reto en el Paraiso (final) part 4. Pages 435-541 (Box  6, Folder  1)
- Reto en el Paraiso (final) part 5. pages 542-606. index (Box  6, Folder  2)
- Reto en el Paraiso (revised draft) pages 1-168 (Box  6, Folder  3)
- Reto en el Paraiso (revised draft) pages 168-338 (Box  6, Folder  4)
- Reto en el Paraiso (revised draft) pages 339-490 (Box  6, Folder  5)
- Reto en el Paraiso (revised draft) pages 491-578 (Box  6, Folder  6)
- Alejandro Morales: Reto en el Paraiso: paperback. Consedo Nacional/ Editorial Gridalbo 1992 (Box  6, Folder  7)
- Alejandro Morales: reto en el Paraiso: paperback. Bilingual Press/Editorial Biligue 1983 (Box  7, Folder  1)
- Aztlan ensoyos sobre literatura chicana (Box  7, Folder  2)
- Significance of the "T"... possible connection to india, mandala; sacret geometry and art (Box  7, Folder  3)
- Peril au Paradis (Box  7, Folder  4)
- Regina Drummond's workshop. Handout on Carl Gustav Jung. A collective Mandala ... historia de la nueva Mexico and morales' the brick people (Box  8, Folder  1)
- Inspiration, archotypes, marxism pritn outs (Box  8, Folder  2)
- Rolando Hindosa the travador's vision of an enduring world. Harold Zapf slammin' in transnational heterotopia (Box  8, Folder  3)
- Rolando Hindosa, Allience to the art writing. Tim Libretti invitation. Y no se trago la tierra. Rolando Hindosa book print out (Box  8, Folder  4)
- Literatura latinoamericana. Poesia, nahuatl y incaica part 1 (Box  8, Folder  5)
- Poesia, nahuatl y incaica part 2 (Box  8, Folder  6)
- Poesia, nahuatl y incaica part 3 (Box  8, Folder  7)
- Caras Vieja y Vino Nuevo inventory (Box  8, Folder  8)
- Alejandro Morales in utopia. Interview with A.Morales. Marvin lewis entry (Box  9, Folder  1)
- El sentimiento de culpa en Reto en el Paraiso de A. Morales. Cara de Caballo. La Verdad Sin Voz: elegy and reparation. Newspaper clippings (Box  9, Folder  2)
- [Poems] (Box  9, Folder  3)
- Travel poems (Box  9, Folder  4)
- Waiting to Happen. Chapters 1, 2 and title. (Box  9, Folder  5)
- Waiting to Happen. Chapters 3 and 4 (Box  9, Folder  6)
- Waiting to Happen. Chapter 5 (Box  9, Folder  7)
- Waiting to Happen. Chapters 1, 2 and intro (draft) (Box  10, Folder  1)
- Waiting to Happen. Chapters 3, 4 and 5 (draft) (Box  10, Folder  2)
- Agreement Publication. Investor aggrements. Charles Trajillo correspondence (Box  10, Folder  3)
- Rosa M correspondence. Alejandro Morales: Waiting to Happen: paperback. Chusma House Publications 2001 (Box  10, Folder  4)
- Waiting to Happen chapters 1 and 2 (Box  10, Folder  5)
- Waiting to Happen chapters 3, 4 and 5 (Box  10, Folder  6)
- En la Frontera I migliori racconti della narrativa chicana: paperback. Gran Via Edizioni 2008 (Box  11, Folder  1)
- Evolving Origins transplanting cultures Literary of the new americans: paperback. Servicio de Publiciones 2002 (Box  11, Folder  2)
- Alejandro Morales; Quetzali, Las Jardenes de Versalles, conference notes, La Panca (Box  11, Folder  3)
- A.Morales Nacion Pequena, The Sign (Box  11, Folder  4)
- A.Morales Mama Concha, Trabajo, LAPD history deputize (Box  11, Folder  5)
- A.Morales The Sign, Guggenheim memorial foundation application (Box  11, Folder  6)
- A.Morales The Parable. Anti Immigration billboard and news clips. The Sign (carol's edition) (Box  11, Folder  7)
- A.Morales Little Nation translated from spanish by Adam Spires (Box  12, Folder  1)
- Tombstone Vigilante article. Supremacist a border worry article. The angrt patriot article. The growing vigilante movement. (Box  12, Folder  2)
- The Conquest and the colony in Song of the Hummingbird by Graciela Limon. The House of Forgetting by Benjamin Alire Saenz. Manfred Flugge correspondence (Box  12, Folder  3)
- The Garden of Versailles (Frank Aranda comments), the conquest and the colony in "the House of Forgetting". The Umbilical Parable (Box  12, Folder  4)
- Pilar Marin Madrazo correspondence. Un Lema Literario en busca de un Escritor. The writers job. Business week. Marquinas of Dreams. (Box  12, Folder  5)
- Maro Garcia Correspondence. Luis Leal Book Award. "Alejandro Morales fiction past, present, future perfect" by Maria Herrera-Sobek. Alejandro Morales (1944-) by Javier Duran (Box  12, Folder  6)
- Somewhere a Child by John French and Alex Morales. Ngugi wa Thiongo, Maria Sobek correspondence. Theoretical issues in chicano latino studies (Box  12, Folder  7)
- Dynamic Identities in Heterotopia. Term mater and the emergence of myth in poems by Alma Villanueva. Cielos de la Tierra by Carmen Boullosa. Escribiendo la Utopia Mexicana a traves del Eterno Apocalips Mexicano (Box  12, Folder  8)
- Las Manifastaciones Del Exilio en este Lugar Sagrado por Poli Delaro. Renato Reguldo describes "culture in the borderlands". Theory on border writing. SPP.gov print outs. Merger with Mexico article (Box  13, Folder  1)
- Restless Serpents compbook. Andando (Box  13, Folder  2)
- Poetry research. Part of Restless Serpents. A. Morales Dona Eulalin (Box  13, Folder  3)
- Essay on "Restless Serpents" part 2 (Box  13, Folder  4)
- Essay on Bernice Zamora's "Restless Serpents" (draf) essay on "Restless Serpents" (final) (Box  13, Folder  5)
- Essay on "Restless Serpents" (draft) (Box  13, Folder  6)
- inter sexual and intertextual codes in the poetry of Bernice Zamora. Anton Chico: New Mexico poetry word analysis (Box  13, Folder  7)
- A.Morales "Watch and you'll understand" Compbook 1 and 2 (Box  14, Folder  1)
- A.Morales Compbook 3 and 4 (Box  14, Folder  2)
- The Maquiladoras. Illegal Immigration Articles (Box  14, Folder  3)
- Correspondence. Fascination or orchids. Notes, newspaper clips, etc. (Box  14, Folder  4)
- A.Morales: the Place of the White Heron. Edited version. Part 1. Pages 1-155 (Box  14, Folder  5)
- A.Morales: the Place of the White Heron. Edited version. Part 2. Pages 156-325 (Box  14, Folder  6)
- A.Morales: the Place of the White Heron reader reports. Correspondence. the Place of the White Heron part 1 (Box  15, Folder  1)
- A.Morales: the Place of the White Heron part 2 (Box  15, Folder  2)
- A.Morales: the Place of the White Heron part 3 (Box  15, Folder  3)
- A.Morales: the Place of the White Heron part 1 pages 1-104 (Box  15, Folder  4)
- A.Morales: the Place of the White Heron part 2 pages 105-248 (Box  15, Folder  5)
- A.Morales: the Place of the White Heron part 3 pages 249-320 (Box  15, Folder  6)
- A.Morales: the Place of the White Heron manuscript part 1 pages 1-92 (Box  16, Folder  1)
- A.Morales: the Place of the White Heron manuscript part 2 pages 93-199 (Box  16, Folder  2)
- A.Morales: the Place of the White Heron manuscript part 3 pages 200-320 Arte Publico Press of the University of Houston (Box  16, Folder  3)
- Flowers by the Doorstep (Box  16, Folder  4)
- The Brick People pages 1-23 and 37-97 (Box  17, Folder  1)
- The Brick People pages 98-169 (Box  17, Folder  2)
- The Brick people pages 170-285 (Box  17, Folder  3)
- Simon Oral History Project. Brick people newsclip, etc. (Box  17, Folder  4)
- Simon Residence interviews. The Tattoed Corpse by Galai Kernahan (Box  17, Folder  5)
- Simon compbooks 1 and 2 (Box  17, Folder  6)
- Essay introduction, Montebello news article (Box  17, Folder  7)
- Simon compbooks 2 and 4 (Box  18, Folder  1)
- Alejandro Morales: El Olvidado Pueblo de Simons: paperback. Universidad de alcala 1992 (Box  18, Folder  2)
- Alejandro Morales: Hombres de Ladrillo: paperback. Arte Publico Press 2010 (Box  18, Folder  3)
- Alejandro Morales: The Brick People: paperback. Arte Publico 1988 (Box  18, Folder  4)
- Alejandro Morales: The Brick People: paperback. Arte Publico 1992 (Box  18, Folder  5)
- Alejandro Morales: The Brick People manuscript (edited) (Box  19, Folder  1)
- Brick People Newsclips, notes, etc. (Box  19, Folder  2)
- Simon, CA clips, articles, etc. (Box  19, Folder  3)
- The Brick People exert and library slip (Box  19, Folder  4)
- Simonsville clips (Box  19, Folder  5)
- "I am the Fox" Los Angeles Herald, Directory, Etc. (Box  19, Folder  6)
- By more than earthly ties compbook and notes (Box  19, Folder  7)
- Simon brick company clips, notes, research (Box  20, Folder  1)
- Simon brick company news clips, advertisements (Box  20, Folder  2)
- Walter Simons clippings etc. (Box  20, Folder  3)
- Contreras family tree, news clips, oral interviews "a company town situated in Los Angeles county" synopsis (Box  20, Folder  4)
- Brick People manuscript (draft) part one (Box  20, Folder  5)
- Brick People manuscript (draft) part two (Box  20, Folder  6)
- the Brick People. Alternative title "Flowers by the Doorstep" manuscript pages 1-126 (Box  20, Folder  7)
- the Brick People. Alternative title "Flowers by the Doorstep" manuscript pages 127-234 (Box  21, Folder  1)
- the Brick People. Alternative title "Flowers by the Doorstep" manuscript pages 233-344 (Box  21, Folder  2)
- the Brick People. Alternative title "Flowers by the Doorstep" manuscript pages 345-500 (Box  21, Folder  3)
- the Brick People. Alternative title "Flowers by the Doorstep" manuscript pages 501-624 (Box  21, Folder  4)
- the Brick People. Alternative title "Flowers by the Doorstep" manuscript pages 625-670 (Box  21, Folder  5)
- the Brick People interviews transcripts Juana Contreras Morales, Cindy Peronto, Josephine Gutierrez (Box  21, Folder  6)
- the Brick People interviews Dona Maria, Luce Navarro Diaz, Alejandro Vargas, Lucille Vargas (Box  22, Folder  1)
- the Brick People interviews Aplinar Urubi, Leonardo Trigueror, Tony Rosa, Bonnie Strayhorn long, Mario Delgados, Delfino Morales (Box  22, Folder  2)
- Brick People Articles (Box  22, Folder  3)
- Hacia una cartografia de Los Angeles a traves de la literatura chicana (Box  22, Folder  4)
- Alejandro Morales: Death of an Anglo: Paperback. Bilingual Press/Editorial Bilingue 1988. Two copies (Box  23, Folder  1)
- Alejandro Morales: La Verdad Sin Voz: Paperback. Joaquin Mortiz 1979 (Box  23, Folder  2)
- Editorial Joaquin Mortiz. La Verdad Sin Voz: copy of original manuscript part 1 (Box  23, Folder  3)
- La Verdad Sin Voz: copy of original Manuscript part 2 (Box  23, Folder  4)
- La Verdad Sin Voz: copy of original Manuscript part 3 (Box  23, Folder  5)
- La Verdad Sin Voz: manuscript pages 1-141. Newsclip (Box  24, Folder  1)
- La Verdad Sin Voz: manuscript pages 142-249 (Box  24, Folder  2)
- La Verdad Sin Voz: manuscript pages 250-344 (Box  24, Folder  3)
- La Verdad Sin Voz: manuscript pages 345-416 (Box  24, Folder  4)
- La Verdad Sin Voz: manuscript (draft) part 1 (Box  24, Folder  5)
- La Verdad Sin Voz: manuscript (draft) part 2 (Box  24, Folder  6)
- La Verdad Sin Voz: manuscript (draft) part 3 (Box  24, Folder  7)
- La Verdad Sin Voz: manuscript (draft) part 4 (Box  25, Folder  1)
- La Verdad Sin Voz: manuscript (draft) part 5 (Box  25, Folder  2)
- Alejandro Morales: Caras Viejas y Vino Nuevo: Hardback. Editorial Joaquin Mortiz 1975 (Box  25, Folder  3)
- Alejandro Morales: Caras Viejas y Vino Nuevo: Paperback. Editorial Joaquin Mortiz 1975. Two Copies (Box  25, Folder  4)
- Caras Viejas y Vino Nuevo: Paperback. Editorial Joaquin Mortiz 1975. Caras Viejas y Vino Nuevo: Hardback. Editorial Joaquin Mortiz 1975 (Box  25, Folder  5)
- Alejandro Morales: Old Faces and New Wine: Paperback. Maize Press 1981 (Box  25, Folder  6)
- Alejandro Morales: Barrio in Flamme: Paperback. Ad est Dell'equatore 2012 (Box  25, Folder  7)
- Alejandro Morales: Barrio on the Edge/Caras Viejas y Vino Nuevo: Paperback. Bilingual Press/Editorial Bilingue 1998 (Box  25, Folder  8)
- Caras Viejas y Vino Nuevo manuscript part 1. Pages 1-28 (Box  25, Folder  9)
- Caras Viejas y Vino Nuevo manuscript part 2. Pages 29-148 (Box  26, Folder  1)
- Barrio on the Edge (translation). Barrio on the Edge cover art (Box  26, Folder  2)
- Choque e interaccion en Caras Viejas y Vino Nuevo y La Verdad Sin Voz de Alejandro Morales by Oscar u. Somoza. Etlinda Gonzales-Berry newsclips (Box  26, Folder  3)
- Old Faces and New Wine translated by Max Martinez (Box  26, Folder  4)
- Rossela Giordano, Carlo Zivielle, David Kliswwa correspondence. The Ending of Our Times (draft) part 1 (Box  26, Folder  5)
- The Ending of Our Times (draft) part 2 (Box  26, Folder  6)
- The Ending of Our Times (draft) part 3 (Box  26, Folder  7)
- The Ending of Our Times notes (Box  26, Folder  8)
- The Ending of Our Times (draft) parts 1-5 (Box  27, Folder  1)
- The Ending of our Times (draft) parts 6-11 (Box  27, Folder  2)
- [Miscellenous Notes] (Box  27, Folder  3)
- The Captain of All These Men of Death notes, edition, bilingual review press, correspondence (Box  27, Folder  4)
- The Captain of All These Men of Death Manuscript 1-171 (Box  27, Folder  5)
- The Captain of All These Men of Death Manuscript 172-333 (Box  27, Folder  6)
- The Captain of All These Men of Death Edited. (Box  27, Folder  7)
- The Captain. News articles, medical journals, tuberculosis research articles (Box  28, Folder  1)
- John Hopkins university article, the patient predator. Treatment of tuberculosis. TB in Canada. What is the right (white) way to be sexual. Illistrating cultural authority. (Box  28, Folder  2)
- The Captain of All these Men of Death (original before restructuring) pages 1-137 (Box  28, Folder  3)
- The Captain of All These Men of Death (original before restructuring) pages 138-302 (Box  28, Folder  4)
- The Captain of All these Men of Death Account book (Box  28, Folder  5)
- The Captain of All these Men of Death manuscript and notebook (Box  28, Folder  6)
- The Captain of All these Men of Death (Edited Version by Carl Penor) pages 1-102 (Box  29, Folder  1)
- The Captain of All these Men of Death (Edited Version by Carl Penor) pages 103-204 (Box  29, Folder  2)
- The Captain of All these Men of Death (Edited Version by Carl Penor) pages 205-341 (Box  29, Folder  3)
- Olive View Sanitorium Entrance, news article and history (Box  29, Folder  4)
- Brief history of Olive View-UCLA. TB Project (Box  29, Folder  5)
- The Captain of All of these Men of Death. Scenes tuberculosis novella (Box  29, Folder  6)
- Alejandro Morales: the Captain of All these Men of Death: Paperback. Bilinguel Press/ Editirial Biligue 2008 (Box  29, Folder  7)
- Bilingual Press letters. The Captain of All these Men of Death (Edited by Linda S. Thurston) Pages 1-149 (Box  30, Folder  1)
- The Captain of All these Men of Death (edited by Linda S. Thurston) pages 150-330 (Box  30, Folder  2)
- Gregory S. Morales "the Captain of All of these Men of Death" April 1, 1996. tuberculosis article, plagues and people, on air, water and places by Hippocrates (Box  30, Folder  3)
- Marcel Triguer, Bilingual Review Press catalog correspondence. (Box  30, Folder  4)
- Tuberculous Paper/ Articles (Box  30, Folder  5)
- Surgeon Errant: the life Writings of William Henry Bucher 1874-1934. Pages 1-53 (Box  30, Folder  6)
- Surgeon Errant: the life Writings of William Henry Bucher 1874-1934. Pages 54-212 (Box  31, Folder  1)
- The Captain of All these Men of Death manuscript pages 1-98 (Box  31, Folder  2)
- The Captain of All these Men of Death manuscript pages 99-302 (Box  31, Folder  3)
- La evolicion narrativa en la obra de Alejandro Morales por Juan Antonio Sanches Jimenez (Box  31, Folder  4)
- the Royal Protomedicato: the Regulations of the medical Profession in the spanish empire. John Tate Lanning edited by John Jay Tepaske (Box  32, Folder  1)
- Alejandro Morales: Plager: Paperback. Dansk udgave-forlaget klim 1993 (Box  32, Folder  2)
- Alejandro Morales: the Rag Doll Plagues: Hardcover. Arte Publico press 1992 (Box  32, Folder  3)
- Alejandro Morales: La Bambola di Pezza: Paperback. Prima Edizione 2002 (Box  32, Folder  4)
- Alejandro morales: the rag Doll Plagues: Paperback. Arte Publico press 1992 (Box  32, Folder  5)
- Rag Doll Plagues compbook and clippings (Box  33, Folder  1)
- Rag Doll Plagues, press release, curriculum vitae, magic realism spring 1994, Leslie Ullman correspondence (Box  33, Folder  2)
- David Sprinkle, John Dolger, Nicolas Kanellos correspondence, alejandro morales bio. Reviews. Publisher aggrements (Box  33, Folder  3)
- "Alejandro Morales fiction past, present, futures perfect" Bilingual Press 1996. Post Modern Humpty-dumpty Morales'es reto en el Paraiso (Box  33, Folder  4)
- [News clips] (Box  33, Folder  5)
- Utopian dreams, apocalyptic nightmares: dystopian images of globalization in recent Mexican and Chicano narrative (Box  33, Folder  6)
- Ventana abierta revista latina. Confluencia. Working through the archive. Convergencies e interferencias: escribir desde las burdes. History literature and the chicano working class novel: a critical review. Uncovering history in the post modern condition. Cuaderno de literatura inglesa y norteamericana. ZAA (Box  33, Folder  7)
- Metro moniter news clips. of nightmares and empires. Narrative Historica post moderna. Narrativia chicana. Novel approach to understanding (Box  34, Folder  1)
- Caras Viejas y Vino Nuevo: essense of the barrio. Barrio life in the fifties and sixties. Tomas Rivera, Porfirio Sanches, Ricardo Barrutia, Seymour Menton, Juan Villages correspondence (Box  34, Folder  2)
- Humanities dean advisory lecture. News clips. Caras Viejas y Vino Nuevo: essense of the barrio. El taller newsletter. La Verdad Sin Voz (Box  34, Folder  3)
- Arnold C. Vento, Galai Kernahan correspondence. Newsclips. La novela chicana de los sententh comentada por su escrtores y criticos (Box  34, Folder  4)
- University of California Santa Barbara, artesan at work: the flesh and blood aesthetics of Alejandro Morales (Box  34, Folder  5)
- Dissertation sintesis historica del Mexicoamericano by Alejandro Morales pages vii-157 (Box  34, Folder  6)
- Dissertation sintesis historica del Mexicoamericano by Alejandro Morales pages 158-309 (Box  34, Folder  7)